# Vasan Routh

# Full Stack Game Developer | Specialized in Multiplayers | Mentor 🕹



vasanrouth@gmail.com 📞 8072290237

Pondicherry, India 

My Portfolio

### **ABOUT ME**

I love coding and playing games . I am a versatile Game Developer with over 7 years of experience, specializing in multiplayer games. And over 9 years of multidisciplinary programming experience. Published multiple games and had the opportunity to lead teams of awesome devs. Part-time Mentoring aspiring students to learn and land jobs in the games industry:)

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Engines**

Unity (7+ Years), Unreal (1 + Years), Godot (1 + Years)

#### Languages

C, C++, C#, JavaScript (ES-ES2023), Java, Python, HTML

## **Cloud/Networking**

AWS, Azure, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase, Playfab, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Socket.IO, Unity Networking (Photon, Mirror)

#### 3D & Art

Blender(3D modeling, texturing, rigging, animating), UI (Photoshop, Adobe XD, Figma), Substance Painter, Alchemy

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor's Degree in Electronics & Communication Engg**

Pondicherry University

05/2017 - 06/2021 | Pondicherry, India

### **Highschool Diploma in Computer Science**

Amalorpavam Hr. Sec. School 03/2015 - 03/2017 | Pondicherry, India

#### **COURSES/CERTIFICATIONS**

# C and C++ Programming

An advanced course on OOPs and DSA

#### **AWS Certified Developer Associate**

A deep course on AWS tools and insights into each service.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Game Dev Mentor [Part-time]

Outscal ☑

06/2024 - Present | New Delhi, India

#### Unity, C++, C#, SFML, Design Patterns, SOLID Architecture

- Coaching students to learn game development, starting from OOPS to building a resume & portfolio,
- Helping them to clear interviews with ease and land jobs in top Game studios.

#### Indie Game Developer [Full time]

Hitkraft Games ☑

02/2024 - Present | Chennai, India

# Playfab, Cloudscript(JS), Google Cloud Run, AWS(Lambda), Photon, Unity, C#

- My own studio, working on a cool multiplayer word game, a mix of Boggle and Candy Crush [Check out] 2.
- Except Art and Audio, everything else is handled by me as a solo dev, from writing net code, local code, and game design too ^^

#### **Lead Game Developer**

Daceq.Ltd ♂

06/2022 - 01/2024 | London, UK

# Unity, C#, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Photon Pun, Playfab, CloudRun, Moralis SDK, EtherJS, Solidity, Elasticsearch, Unity Cloud Build(CI/CD), Gamelift, Lambda, DynamoDB

- Lead a team of 8 to build an MMORTS game made with Unity (Hosting map servers, Buildings movement, Troop training, Combat mechanics, etc) [Check out] ☑
- My other work includes building a mix of Card + RTS genre-type mobile game for both Android and IOS platforms. [Check out] □

#### **Lead Game Developer**

Creatr Studios Inc ☑

03/2021 - 06/2022 | Toronto, Canada

# Unity, C#, GraphQL, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Photon, Playfab, CloudRun, Enjin SDK, Facebook SDK, Azure VM

- Led a team for an NFT game project that executes blockchain requests using GraphQL queries/mutations, safely in the Google Cloud Run (NodeJS) platform. [Check out] []
- Utilized Photon Cloud to transmit player inputs through RPC calls, keeping the game state in sync, with each call cross-verified by PlayFab CloudScript.

#### **Indie Game Developer**

FrostDrakeGames ☑

02/2019 - 03/2021 | Pondicherry, India

### Unity, C#, JS, Firebase, Playfab, CloudRun, Blender

- Worked on multiple freelance game projects using Unity,
- Tricky Bounce 2 & Bubble shooter 2 both have now over 10M+ downloads,
- Parallelly worked on my personal project, <u>Gambit</u> ☑, <u>creating 3D models</u> ☑ and assembling the entire web3 game, including the server and local components. Even hosted a Kickstarter campaign ☑!